<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Tadd Mencer</title>
    <link href="http://taddmencer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://taddmencer.com" />
    <updated>2022-09-02T12:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://taddmencer.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to Start an Online Business on the Cheap</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/how-to-start-an-online-business-on-the-cheap/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/how-to-start-an-online-business-on-the-cheap/</id>
            <category term="Entrepreneur"/>
            <category term="Business"/>

        <updated>2022-09-02T12:10:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/onlinebusiness.jpg" alt="How to Start an Online Business on the Cheap" />
                     Did you know that you can create an online, ecommerce business, with no inventory, for as little as $6? NOTE: Some of the links are affiliate links, which means I get a small kick-back if you use those links. I only suggest what I&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/onlinebusiness.jpg" alt="How to Start an Online Business on the Cheap" />
                <header class="post-header">
<h2 class="intro">Did you know that you can create an online, ecommerce business, with no inventory, for as little as $6?</h2>
</header>
<p class="affil msg msg--info">NOTE: Some of the links are affiliate links, which means I get a small kick-back if you use those links. I only suggest what I personally use.</p>
<p>Everyone is looking for that next big side hustle. Something to make a little extra money. Or a full-time living. Especially as we’re pulling out of the nightmare of 2020 and trying to pick up the pieces of our lives. We want to create something of our own so if our job closes shop, we have something to fall back on. After all, we can only rely on government handouts for so long before that dries up.</p>
<h2 id="enter-print-on-demand">Enter Print-On-Demand</h2>
<p>POD, or “print-on-demand”, is when a customer orders your product, that order goes to a printing company, they print it and ship it to your customer. No inventory, no mess. In most cases, your customer doesn’t even realize anything is different. In the past print on demand companies didn’t produce the best results. It had resulted in shoddy print quality, bad products in general, and a general lack of features. Today, entrepreneurs and influences all run on this framework, and its’ something you can accomplish with very little financial investment and some free time. I’ve been working a full-time job while setting up my shops, so I know it can be done. Here are a few simple steps that you can do, get set up, and start your own e-commerce business today!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><a href="https://www.printful.com/a/3531971:f8bd55c723e78cce108337c3ae036488" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/printful.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/311/responsive/printful-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="680" height="200"></figure></a></p>
<h3 id="sign-up-a-free-printful-account">Sign up a free Printful account</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.printful.com/a/3531971:f8bd55c723e78cce108337c3ae036488" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Printful</a> is a fully functioning print-on-demand company that I’ve been using for a while now. It’s free to sign up and use. You have the ability to print anything from t-shirts to phone cases to backpacks and laptop sleeves. Are you into custom mugs? Printful can print those for you too! Once there, you‘ll of course need to set up your profile, billing information, PayPal, etc. Printful has a load of great tutorials to get you moving. They also have a great community and support, so you’re never alone! One of the things to remember is Printful isn’t a store itself. People can’t come to yourstore.printful.com and shop. Which is fine! That’s for the next step.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><a href="https://launchcart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://taddmencer.com/images/posts/launchcart.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Sign up for a free LaunchCart account" width="680" height="200"></figure></a></p>
<h3 id="sign-up-for-launchcart">Sign up for LaunchCart</h3>
<p><a href="https://launchcart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LaunchCart</a> is a free* online eCommerce system that allows you to create robust stores, without having to pay anything out of pocket. They take a small percentage of each sale, which means the better your store runs, the more they make. Which is an incentive for them to work hard to make your store be the best! Once you sign up for your free account, you select “Super Powers (apps)” in the left menu and enable Printful. Follow the prompts to connect your Printful account to LaunchCart and you’re ready to go!</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">* As of recently, LaunchCart changed a few features and added a paid plan. Still free, but it's not as feature rich as it once was. In the near future I'll add some other possibilities.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/f9104qgpmgo35448C65B435586A989" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://taddmencer.com/images/posts/namecheap.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Get a cheap domain name with NameCheap" width="680" height="200"></figure></a></p>
<h3 id="get-a-domain-name-from-namecheap">Get a Domain Name from NameCheap</h3>
<p>This is the only step that costs money, but it’s not a huge investment. I highly recommend <a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/f9104qgpmgo35448C65B435586A989" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NameCheap</a>. I use them exclusively for my domain name purchasing needs, as well as for a Wordpress site I run. They have a lot of great services, but their prices are fantastic. Any time I had issues or questions, their staff was knowledgeable and helpful. Just type the name you’re interested in to see if it’s available. They’ll also recommend other names if yours is taken. Very nice! And as you see, right now you can get a .com for $5.98 a year, which is really amazing! Now that you have everything ordered, you can go back to your LaunchCart store, go to “Settings” and click “Custom Domain” and follow the easy-to-understand instructions to add a domain.</p>
<p><strong>To recap:</strong> For less than $6 a year you can start a fully functioning eCommerce business. Have zero inventory you need to manage. And start building a future for yourself, your family, and your wellbeing.</p>
<p>I’ll be creating more like this in the near future. More step-by-step guides. I’ll be diving more into the marketing aspect, SEO, and general business practice. How to drive organic traffic. Comment below if you have any questions!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/about-2/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/about-2/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T16:06:54-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/tm-about.jpg" alt="" />
                     I write stories, do voices, make &amp; play video games, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons. I run Cubelab Media. A father, husband, and generally friendly guy. I’ve been constructing websites, generating digital marketing campaigns, and creating games for over twenty years. I have experience in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/tm-about.jpg" alt="" />
                <header class="post-header">
<h2 class="intro">I write stories, do voices, make &amp; play video games, and Dungeons &amp; Dragons. I run Cubelab Media. A father, husband, and generally friendly guy.</h2>
</header>
<p>I’ve been constructing websites, generating digital marketing campaigns, and creating games for over twenty years. I have experience in software like Adobe Photoshop, Affinity Designer, Blender 3D, and Unity 3D. I have created game assets for both 2D and 3D games. I have also established branding for products across different media, such as web and print.</p>
<p>An avid storyteller, I am the most thrilled when building worlds and story that enthrall and inspire. I love creating deep, lore rich plots and quests for Dungeons &amp; Dragons, or crafting an ecosystem of history for video game use.</p>
<p>I take great pleasure in building something to explore. It’s the experience. The thrill of reading or seeing or encountering something unique.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: 18.4px; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal); outline: 3px solid rgba(var(--primary-color-rgb), 0.55)  !important;" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/i-am-tadd.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/313/responsive/i-am-tadd-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="1080" height="400"></figure>
<h3 id="professional-experience">PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE</h3>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><em>Game Design/Development &amp; Project Experience</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Forging interactive low poly 3D game levels using Blender and Unity</li>
<li>Designing UI/UX menus, displays, and assets for in-game utilization</li>
<li>Creating exciting experiences for players including the ideation of characters and obstacles</li>
<li>Utilizing Blender and Unity to create an augmented reality prototype</li>
<li>Designed Circus Big Pop Lite iOS Mobile Game in LUA Language which has been downloaded over 2000 times.</li>
<li>Constructed prototype Project Marcus PC first-person 3D using Unity and Blender 3D</li>
</ul>
<p class="msg msg--success msg--highlight "><em>Communications</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Organizing projects with out of country developers for mobile and web use</li>
<li>Weaving multi-plot stories and quests used in Dungeons &amp; Dragons</li>
<li>Possessing strong verbal and written communication skills</li>
</ul>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><em>Web and Marketing</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Establishing brand structures for better recognition across multiple platforms and products</li>
<li>Structuring email campaigns that increase user engagement</li>
<li>Constructing mobile web prototypes that utilize modern practices</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Goal is Not a Plan</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/a-goal-is-not-a-plan/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/a-goal-is-not-a-plan/</id>
            <category term="Business"/>

        <updated>2022-01-21T12:07:05-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/310/a-goal-is-not-a-plan.jpg" alt="A Goal is Not a Plan" />
                     In a previous job I was honored and blessed to be both the marketing manager and project manager. I was in charge of making things happen successfully and on time. I was head of a team, and it felt good. We increased productivity, sales,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/310/a-goal-is-not-a-plan.jpg" alt="A Goal is Not a Plan" />
                <header class="post-header">
<h2 class="intro">In a previous job I was honored and blessed to be both the marketing manager and project manager. I was in charge of making things happen successfully and on time.</h2>
</header>
<p>I was head of a team, and it felt good. We increased productivity, sales, and efficiency. We were a well oiled machine!</p>
<p>However, during a conversation with the CEO, he told me he wanted to increase sales and launch new products. I asked a simple question, “Do you have a plan to accomplish these goals?”</p>
<p>He looked annoyed, turned his monitor to show me the custom sales reporting system we had, and said “This is my plan. Sales.”</p>
<h3 id="having-a-goal-is-not-a-plan">Having a goal is not a plan.</h3>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, you need to have a goal. Know where you’re going. Why you’re going there. If your goal is to lose 15 pounds, you need to figure out how to get there. Willing yourself there, I can attest, will not shed that body weight. Figuring out an exercise plan and sticking to it will.</p>
<p>When you start your business or organization, make sure you have an outline how to achieve your goals, as well as what those goals are. The outline is a guide, and may be adjusted with time. However, having that guide, that solid plan, will help you to reach your destination.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>It&#x27;s Been a While </title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/its-been-a-while/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/its-been-a-while/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:15:13-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     It's time to get off my tuff and do be more than just another number in the tally of people who could have been. Once upon a time, I tried to take up this blogging business. Made an attempt, anyway. I have folders in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
    <h2 id="its-time-to-get-off-my-tuff-and-do-be-more-than-just-another-number-in-the-tally-of-people-who-could-have-been">
      It's time to get off my tuff and do be more than just another number in the tally of people who could have been.
    </h2>

  <p>
    <br><br>Once upon a time, I tried to take up this blogging business. Made an attempt, anyway. I have folders in Google Drive with starts and stops to articles I wanted to write.<br><br><strong>Life has a way of changing what you’re planning, doesn’t it?<br></strong><br>I decided it was time to start this website again. I have a lot going on, but I want a place to document some of my starts, stops, lessons learned, and painful mistakes.
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li>I plan on writing weekly, revealing some things I’m doing, sharing resources, and providing tools that I find have worked.
</li><li>I plan on recording different videos, both entertaining and educational. Different channels, and niching down as much as possible.
</li><li>I plan on creating products, and telling you guys what works and doesn’t work.</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    I hope that by doing all of this, it helps someone to success in this wonderfully wacky world of online business and entrepreneurship. Or, at least keep someone from doing the same dumb mistakes I do.
<br>
<br>I wish us both luck.
<br>
<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
<div><div style="width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:90%;position:relative;"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://giphy.com/embed/tZCkL6BsL2AAo" width="100%" height="100%" style="position:absolute" frameBorder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowFullScreen></iframe></div></div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why I&#x27;m Breaking Up With WordPress</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/why-im-breaking-up-with-wordpress/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/why-im-breaking-up-with-wordpress/</id>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2022-01-21T12:33:12-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/312/why-im-breaking-up-with-wordpress_Goodbye.jpg" alt="" />
                    Like many before me, I have to admit … I’m leaving WordPress. It’s not because there is anything wrong with the CMS. In fact, I absolutely love it. It has been a great platform to work with, and I’ll use it in my professional world.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/312/why-im-breaking-up-with-wordpress_Goodbye.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Like many before me, I have to admit … I’m leaving WordPress. It’s not because there is anything wrong with the CMS. In fact, I absolutely love it. It has been a great platform to work with, and I’ll use it in my professional world.</p>
<p>It’s not because of anything Elegant Themes, the developers of Divi did. I love that theme, and I feel it’s been a great boost to so many niche sites it would be foolish not to use it. Flexible and useful.</p>
<p>There are, in fact, two main reasons I’m severing my ties with the fantastic CMS.</p>
<h3 id="the-hosting-was-getting-worse">The hosting was getting worse</h3>
<p>I’ve bounced around to a few different web hosts in the past. I have to say, for what I can afford (which isn’t much) they all pretty much sucked. And the last host I was on for shared servers really didn’t help. And while Dreamhost is probably fine for static sites that really don’t have a lot to work with, they’re not strong enough for my needs. And I’m not paying $100+ a year for a host that doesn’t fit my needs.</p>
<h3 id="wordpress-outgrew-me">WordPress Outgrew Me</h3>
<p>Strange to say, but WordPress got bigger than I would ever really need for my pitiful little blog. I realized that I didn’t need all the features that it offered. I didn’t need databases and intense SEO and taxonomies. I didn’t have a call for it. I’m not big enough, and honestly probably won’t be. If I get to a point that I need it again, WordPress will be patiently waiting for me.</p>
<h3 id="hello-publii-hello-github">Hello, Publii. Hello, GitHub.</h3>
<p>So here I am. I’ve moved to a <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> system. I’m running a static site using <a href="https://getpublii.com/">Publii</a>, which is a light and easy software. Nothing fancy. Fast, light, and reasonable.</p>
<p>I may go back to WordPress again. As I said, if I grow to a point that I need it, I know where to go.</p>
<p>Maybe.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Get More Done by Walking It Off</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/get-more-done-by-walking-it-off/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/get-more-done-by-walking-it-off/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:28:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A few years ago I had sent a few questions via email to one of my favorite writers, R.A. Salvatore. The premise was simple, asking a professional author for advice to someone aspiring to be the same. Some of the answer I expected: Read whatever&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1336"><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l.jpg"><img loading="lazy"  title="people_beach_shadow_1326788_l" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/309/responsive/people_beach_shadow_1326788_l-199x300-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="199" height="300" /></figure></a>A few years ago I had sent a few questions via email to one of my favorite writers, <a href="http://www.rasalvatore.com" target="_blank">R.A. Salvatore</a>. The premise was simple, asking a professional author for advice to someone aspiring to be the same.</p>
<p>Some of the answer I expected: Read whatever you can, pay attention, go to workshops and connect with other authors.</p>
<p>One thing he said to me was surprising: <strong>go for a walk</strong>.</p>
<p>Fresh air and a bit of exercise is <em>great</em> for your mind, body and soul. If you're been sitting in your chair in front of a computer for hours you're going to end up writing uninspired and unmotivated pieces. So, every so often, get out of your chair and go outside. The fresh air will clear any cobwebs, get the blood flowing to your legs and head and hopefully give you that boost you've been needing!</p>
<p>Sometimes to get the most done on a project you need to stop working on it. Take a break. Breath.</p>
<p>Thanks, Mr. Salvatore, for taking the time to email a fan-boy back and giving me great advice! It's much appreciated!</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What Is It That Inspires You?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/what-is-it-that-inspires-you/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/what-is-it-that-inspires-you/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:28:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Where do you find things that get your mind moving? What motivates you? Where do you find the inspiration to continue writing words? Creating works of art? Caring for others? Loving on another? I need to find my sweet spot. The place where I feel&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="alignright size-full wp-image-1329"><img loading="lazy"  style="margin-right:10px;margin-bottom:10px;" title="pines_water_pond_283363_o" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/pines_water_pond_283363_o.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/308/responsive/pines_water_pond_283363_o-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="300" height="200" /></figure>Where do you find things that get your mind moving?</p>
<p>What motivates you?</p>
<p>Where do you find the inspiration to continue writing words?
Creating works of art?
Caring for others?
Loving on another?</p>
<p>I need to find my sweet spot. The place where I feel inspired, excited and motivated. I try and teach my oldest son how to find joy in little things. As we drove through the city I challenged him to find details and little things and get excited about it. He did it with gusto and soon was pointing out architextures, trees, squirrels on the street and even how a telephone pole was leaning.</p>
<p><strong>Here is a challenge for you:</strong> Where can you find inspiration? Find small details of a day and mentally record them. Things that strike you in just a way. It doesn't have to be earth shaking. Something simple like a shadow against an object or a phrase someone said. Something you read.
Find <em>something</em> that inspired or entranced you, and comment on this post. Tell me what it was and, if you can, what stood out to you.</p>
<p>Everyone needs to find something to be inspired by.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>5 Video Games of My Youth</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/5-video-games-of-my-youth/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/5-video-games-of-my-youth/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:28:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Video games are the very apex of a child's life. At least these days. When I was young we didn't have the same games they have now, but there had been some pretty big influences for me, even at a young age. The original, 8bit&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Video games are the very apex of a child's life. At least these days. When I was young we didn't have the same games they have now, but there had been some pretty big influences for me, even at a young age.</p>
<p><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Super_Mario_Bros._box.png"><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;margin:7px;" title="Super_Mario_Bros._box" border="0" alt="Super_Mario_Bros._box" align="left" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-xs.png 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-sm.png 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-md.png 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-lg.png 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-xl.png 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Super_Mario_Bros._box_thumb-2xl.png 1600w"  width="45" height="62" /></a></p>
<h3>1) Super Mario Brothers</h3>
<p>The original, 8bit beast that flag-shipped the first Nintendo Entertainment System. Even to this day I don't know how or why a plumber would be saving any world from giant, man-eating shrooms, duck-turtles that can also fly or fire-breathing dragon-turtles. But he did, and I'm sure the Princess (who was always getting snatched!) was grateful.</p>
<p><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/LegendoftheRedDragon.jpg"><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;margin:7px;" title="LegendoftheRedDragon" border="0" alt="LegendoftheRedDragon" align="left" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/LegendoftheRedDragon_thumb-2xl.jpg 1600w"  width="73" height="65" /></a></p>
<h3>2) Legend of the Red Dragon</h3>
<p>This was a popular BBS (Bulletin Board System) game that was all text. This pre-dated the internet and online gaming, and for whatever reason I loved it. Story based, simple adventuring and enjoyable. I'd spend my allowed time (60 minutes a day on a particular BBS) playing this and soon was a champion. I even have an 11x17 poster from it, which even today looks pretty boss.</p>
<h3><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Wolfenstein-3d.jpg"><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;margin:7px;" title="Wolfenstein-3d" border="0" alt="Wolfenstein-3d" align="left" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Wolfenstein-3d_thumb-2xl.jpg 1600w"  width="49" height="57" /></a>3) Wolfenstein 3D</h3>
<p>Any FPS (first person shooter) veteran will tell you they cut their teeth on this game. Classic &quot;American soldier vs Nazi&quot; game. This is known as the for-runner for modern FPS games.</p>
<h3><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Machunt.jpg"><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;margin:7px;" title="Machunt" border="0" alt="Machunt" align="left" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/Machunt_thumb.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Machunt_thumb-2xl.jpg 1600w"  width="59" height="58" /></a>4) Machine Hunter</h3>
<p>This was a great top-down shooter from 1997. It's one of those highly un-loved games that I played (and still do!) regularly. The play is great, graphics and fun and there is just enough challenge to make it fun, but not to the point of throwing my controller through the screen. </p>
<blockquote>   
<p>&quot;The objective of the game is for the player to shoot down robots and take control of them. Once the player has taken control of the robot, he/she has the robot's weapons and upgrades. The player can take control of many different types of robots. The player must rescue all the civilians in order to proceed to the next stage. The game has a two player cooperative mode.</p>
<p>Throughout the game, the player moves his way shooting a robots, aliens, mutants and huge vehicles that tries to impede the player's progress. There is a total of 9 robots the player can take control of, each with different abilities and weapons.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://taddmencer.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/Metroid_boxart.jpg"><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;margin:7px;" title="Metroid_boxart" border="0" alt="Metroid_boxart" align="left" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/Metroid_boxart_thumb.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/307/responsive/Metroid_boxart_thumb-2xl.jpg 1600w"  width="69" height="98" /></a>5) Metroid</p>
<p>One of my favorite, all time, side-scroller adventure games. Released in 1986 for the Nintendo I remember devouring this game for hours. Looking for every item possible. When Super Metroid was released in 1994 I was more than just a little exited and wasn't disappointed. Again, spent untold hours neglecting my now wife playing this game.</p>
<p><em>&quot;Samus travels through the caverns of the planet Zebes to stop the Space Pirates from exploiting the Metroid species for galactic domination.&quot;</em>&#160;</p>
<p align="center"><strong>What games did you grow up with?</strong></p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Planning for a Stress Free Project</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/planning-for-a-stress-free-project/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/planning-for-a-stress-free-project/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:28:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    With the third baby on it’s way, the final room on our second floor needed to be finished. That meant running electrical, cleaning the dusty walls, patching cracks and holes left from the aging plaster, painting and carpeting. That is a lot of work and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><img loading="lazy" style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:right;padding-top:0;border-width:0;margin:0 0 10px 10px;" title="everystockphoto-59752-o" border="0" alt="everystockphoto-59752-o" align="right" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/everystockphoto-59752-o.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/306/responsive/everystockphoto-59752-o-2xl.jpg 1600w"  width="171" height="240" />With the third baby on it’s way, the final room on our second floor needed to be finished. That meant running electrical, cleaning the dusty walls, patching cracks and holes left from the aging plaster, painting and carpeting. That is a lot of work and honestly, seems over-whelming if I just look at the list.</p>
<p>Projects in general are like this. If you look at the whole of the project, you’ll see nothing but trouble. So many tasks, so much to do.</p>
<p>Every project needs to be attacked in this way.</p>
<p><strong>First. List out what needs done.</strong></p>
<p>This is the daunting part of the task. Trying to figure out all the things needed done to complete your project is exhausting mentally. However, it’s a necessary, if not mentally painful, step everyone needs to take. This helps you to see the scope of your job and help to schedule it properly.</p>
<p><strong>Second. Forget the stress.</strong></p>
<p>Stupid sounding step, but this is imperative if you want to continue. As you look at the mountain of tasks stress comes charging in. Often times each task is accompanied by sub-tasks and those have tasks of their own. It can quickly become a monster list of baddies you need to combat to reach your goal. </p>
<p>However, don’t stress out over the girth of your newly written list. Become the next step will help you.</p>
<p><strong>Third. Set you goal time.</strong></p>
<p>For me, it’s easy. Get the room done before the baby is born on September 7th (or before like his brothers). This allows you to break down you daily tasks in the next step.</p>
<p><strong>Fourth. Make an easily achievable schedule.</strong></p>
<p>Sit down with your list, look at a calendar and your other daily duties and start breaking things down. </p>
<p>For instance, one day my task was simply to look at the room I need to work on. That’s it. I can think about how to tackle my complete job and even visualize the end product. Consider how to attack certain areas and gain needed confidence.</p>
<p>Another day I simply scheduled to run one single wire to the basement.</p>
<p>These little goals will help you get excited as you cross finished items off your task list. It will energize you and propel you to the finish line faster than you realize.</p>
<p><strong>Fifth. Get going!</strong></p>
<p>Sure, easier said than done, but once you get all your tasks listed, scheduled and ready to roll it makes your entire job a lot easier. Schedule an hour a day to just work on your project. If I can get to the room, run a wire, drill some holes, patch some cracks, before you know it that room will be done and ready for baby. So far, I’ve done pretty well getting things rolling.</p>
<p><strong>Sixth. Motivate and reward.</strong></p>
<p>Every day you need to find a way to reward yourself. Whether it’s watching an extra episode of a show you enjoy or a few pieces of chocolate. Reward yourself and keep motivated. Don’t give up. </p>
<p>This isn’t a comprehensive guide, of course. These are suggestions. Things that have worked for me. </p>
<p>Are there any steps you take when planning a project?</p>



            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Beware of the Walls of Distractions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tadd Mencer</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://taddmencer.com/beware-of-the-walls-of-distractions/"/>
        <id>http://taddmencer.com/beware-of-the-walls-of-distractions/</id>

        <updated>2022-01-21T11:28:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I sat down at my computer, as I had so many times, ready to work on a project. I crack my knuckles, get my serious face on and go at it. This is how I'd like to say I am. Unwavering, unflinching and heads-down on&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="alignright size-full wp-image-1299"><a href="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/walls.jpg"><img loading="lazy"  title="walls" src="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/walls.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-xs.jpg 300w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-sm.jpg 480w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-md.jpg 768w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://taddmencer.com/media/posts/305/responsive/walls-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="400" height="266" /></figure></a>I sat down at my computer, as I had so many times, ready to work on a project. I crack my knuckles, get my serious face on and go at it.</p>
<p>This is how I'd like to say I am. Unwavering, unflinching and heads-down on my work. Sadly, it's not. I'm easily distracted.</p>
<p>The world is full of these "distraction walls". It thrives on it.</p>
<p>Video games.</p>
<p>YouTube.</p>
<p>Hulu.</p>
<p>NetFlix.</p>
<p>Blogs and RSS feeds.</p>
<p>Emails.</p>
<p>We're bombarded day-in and day-out with new information and noise. It's not a wonder people can't get things done. We're so distracted by life.</p>
<p>Even things that look good like extra work can be a distraction on what you need to do.</p>
<p>I've made it a goal to seriously look at my life, see what I need to keep and what I need to purge. Sometimes it's hard. I used to be in a band and write music, but I recently came to grips that stage of life is over. I purged myself of software and equipment.</p>
<p>I also have been an avid gamer, logging hundreds if not thousands of hours playing first-person-shooters and role-playing-games. When I realized it wasn't aiding in my goal (being a writer) I removed those games from my computer.</p>
<p>There are other distractions I need to slowly weed out. I love watching movies and such. However, it may come to the point where I need to block certain websites from my laptop in order to keep myself from becoming distracted.</p>
<p>It's hard to admit. However, in the end, it's better for me. Less to focus on means more focus to use on what I want and need.</p>
<p>What sort of things distract you from meeting your life-goal? Are these something to pursue or should they be purged?</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
